妈妈
Mum!
妈咪
心是黑暗的森林
THE HEART IS A DARK FOREST
妈妈
Mum!
让门开着
Leave it open!
早上好
Morning.
你什么时候到家的
When did you get home?
我没能睡上 临近预演了…
I hardly got any sleep, and the rehearsal starts soon...
那你回来干嘛
Why did you come at all?
我能多待十五分钟吗
Do I get 15 more minutes?
好吧 十分钟…
Alright, ten minutes...
这是一款以传统方式生产的天然蜂蜜
This is a natural product from traditional beekeeping.
因其天然的粘稠度…
Because of its natural consistency...
不适合12个月以下的婴儿
honey isn't suitable for infants under 12 months.
你好 小天使
Hello, little angel.
现在能用洗手间吗 - 当然 你想用多久都行
Can I go to the bathroom now? - Sure. As long as you want.
快跑 小马驹 快跑
Run, pony, run!
简直荒唐
That's dumb.
怎么了 - 一切都好
What happened? - Everything alright.
不 求你了 别
No, please, no!
你们能做到这个吗 用两个勺子
Can you do that, can you make both spoons stick?
你瞎了吗
Are you blind?
恩哼 你把汤匙放在了眼皮上
Ey, you've got spoons on your eyes.
好看吗 - 我想有些大
Do I look pretty? - I think it's a little too big.
背后还没拉上
It's not closed yet.
去坐到你的椅子上
Go sit on your chair.
今晚我想和你一起去 - 好极了
I wanted to come with you tonight. - Great.
不好吗 - 不是 当然好
No? - Yes, sure.
我不打算久待 演奏完就走
I didn't plan to stay long, just play, then leave.
因为我要跟来
Because I want to come?
别胡乱猜忌 昨天是在理查兹举办的派对
Nonsense! They had a party at Richards yesterday.
我不是受到邀请 是因为提洛要去
I wasn't invited, but still went because of Thilo.
跟提洛有什么关系
Why Thilo?
因为晚上在理查兹举办派对的 是提洛
Thilo gave a dinner party last night at Richards.
是吗 我不知道
Really? I didn't know.
为什么一到星期五你就很烦人 - 因为我就是让人厌烦
You are always tired on Friday. - I'm ALWAYS tired!
提洛为什么要举办派对
Why did Thilo hold the party?
要咖啡吗
Coffee?
因为 卖掉了很多画作
Sold lots of his paintings.
那些人简直了
Those people were awful.
爸爸 我能打扫你的小提琴吗 - 好啊 我的女儿
Dad, can I clean your violin? - Yes, my daughter.
尤尔根在问候你
Juergen sends his regards.
不会吧
Never!
是真的 “替我向玛丽问好，问她过得怎样” 等等
Yes, "Say hi to Marie, how is she" and so on.
之后我在男厕时 和乔纳森愉快地交谈
Later I had a nice talk with Jonathan in the men's room.
仍旧是谈论音乐 还是流行的东西
Is this still about music, or just this pop thing?
流行的东西
Pop.
明天我打算早些回家 好和你一起用早餐
I wanted to come home early tomorrow, to have breakfast with you.
或者去散散步
Or maybe we could take a walk.
把孩子们交给你妈妈
Your mother could have the children.
今晚我问问她 - 请求她明天时照看孩子们
I asked her to look after them tonight. - Then ask her to do it tomorrow.
去散步吗 - 是 或者聊天 天啊鬼知道要做什么
Take a walk? - Yes, or talking or God knows what!
你们这两个小天使
You little angels!
你牙齿上有东西
There's something on your tooth!
显得很傻 - 那真糟了
It'll be totally stupid. - Or great!
算了
Whatever.
祝你玩得开心 - 开心？该交房租了
Have fun! - Fun? It's to pay the rent!
我不想要了
I don't want it anymore.
你也并不想要
You don't want it either.
别自说自话 - 我是说真的
Speak for yourself. - It's true!
你想要什么
What do YOU want?
我想要你负起责任来 - 那就好啊
I want you to want it too. - Then everything's good!
如果你不付房租会发生什么
What happens if you don't pay your rent?
那在某个时候 你们就必须要搬走
Then you have to move at some point.
莱昂尼 你在做什么
Leonie, what are you doing?
我把我的洋娃娃放进了爸爸的提琴箱里 他还没有…
I put my doll into Dad's case and he hasn't...
发现
noticed yet.
你们觉得这样行吗
Do you think it'll work?
最好再离电视机远一点
Better leave the TV alone.
我会在它们播完前回来
I'm back before they've finished.
无论对方说什么都不要开门 水在餐桌上
And don't open the door, whatever they say. Water is on the table.
我很快回来
I'll be back soon.
托马斯
Thomas!
托马斯？
Thomas?
你好
Hello.
抱歉 托马斯刚来过没
Sorry, didn't Thomas just came in?
我们走吧
Let's go.
玛丽 这是我们的儿子保罗
Marie, that's our son Paul.
我想给我们的儿子取名保罗 你却不愿意
I wanted to name our son Paul, but you didn't want to.
坐好
Sit down.
你们进庭院去说 好吗
And you go into the garden, okay?
玛丽
Marie!
你总是要我冷静 我有种知觉 你是随口糊弄我
You always calm me down. I have a feeling, you say it doesn't exist.
你弄错了 我没有打电话
You're wrong, I didn't phone.
总有一天 我不会再有任何感觉…
One day, I won't have feelings anymore...
我感觉就像 我精神上依赖着别人的谎言
I'll feel like being on psychotropics, dependent on other peoples lies.
拜托
Please!
我该怎么脱身 - 玛丽 别无理取闹 我必须要工作
How do I get off? - Marie, don't flip. I HAVE to work!
也许我也应当工作 - 我们一定会处理好这些的
Perhaps I have to work too. - We'll have to organise it somehow.
我必须要处理好
I'll have to organise it!
我必须离开了 - 我也是
I have to go. - Me too.
等等
Stay.
拜托 你做的很出色
Come on, you're doing great.
马上就到头了 小的孩子将上幼稚园了
It'll be over soon, the little one will be in the nursery.
我们需要你 其他女人都能做到的
We need you. Other women can do it.
那我不算是一个女人 - 你是里面最出色的
Then I'm not a woman. - You're the best!
我回来了
I'm back.
你好
Hello?
有谁在那里吗
Is anybody here?
有啊 我们在
Yes, we are!
当然
Of course!
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
公车没来 - 你骑车去的…
The bus didn't come... - You cycled.
我收拾了屋子
I tidied the mess.
来
Come on.
过来吧孩子们
Are you coming?
我能接电话吗 - 不能
Can I go to the phone? - No.
估计是外婆 她想知道要不要过来
Bet it's Grandma. She wants to know if she should come.
是吗
Alright.
你听到你爸爸说的了 外婆明天过来
You heard what your father said. Grandma's coming tomorrow.
我去问问她 - 别去
I'll ask her. - That's enough!
喂 - 真是够了
Hello? - That can't be true!
莱昂尼
Leonie!
喂 妈妈 喂
Hello mum? Hello?
喂
Hello?
喂 妈妈 - 我在
Hello mum. - Yes?
你挂掉了电话吗 - 什么
Did you drop the receiver? - Why?
你刚刚打给我
You just phoned me.
你疯了吗 这真是热情的问候
Are you crazy? That's a warm-hearted reception!
冷静点 我就问一下 - 是那样吗 你和我说话的方式…
Calm down. I just asked a question. - Really, the way you talk to me...
喂
Hello?
等等…
Wait...
等等 要等什么 - 我回头打给你
Wait, for what? - I'll call you back.
我应该过来还是不 - 之后再说 拜
Should I come or not? - Then do something else, bye.
刚才电话里是谁
Who was on the phone?
你忘记关掉厨房的煤气了
You forgot to switch off the gas in the kitchen.
电话里是谁
Who was on the phone?
外婆
Grandma!
Grandma.
外婆…
Grandma...
晚安 莱昂尼
Good night, Leonie.
我们并排坐在池塘边…
We sat together at the pond...
艾略特 我还有月亮
Elliot, me and the moon.
我们有很多话谈…
We had lots to talk about...
莱昂尼 告诉过最早打来电话是谁
Leonie, tell me who phoned earlier.
我知道不是外婆 我跟她谈过
I know it wasn't grandma, I talked to her.
快点 莱昂尼 告诉我
Come on, Leonie, tell me.
当小鸟看见鸭子…
When the little bird saw the duck...
你在伤心吗
Are you sad?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我在发愁
I'm worried.
为什么
Why?
如果你没把洋娃娃放进爸爸的提琴箱…
If you hadn't put your doll in Dad's case...
没关系的 妈妈 爸爸向汉斯借了一把小提琴
No problem, Mum, Dad borrowed a violin from Hanns.
但是不要跟他说是我告诉你的 - 什么
But don't tell him that I told you. - What?
爸爸早些时候在电话里跟我讲的
It was Dad on the phone today earlier.
我想是的 - 我们在午饭的时候还讲过
I thought so. - We also spoke at lunch time.
你为什么没有告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
看到了吗 现在生我的气 即使不关我的事
See? Now you're cross with me, even though it's not my fault.
胡说八道
Nonsense!
哎呀 - 他说了什么
Ouch! - What did he say?
他发现了我的洋娃娃在提琴箱里…
That he found my doll in the case...
他没有生气 因为他从汉斯那儿借到一把提琴
and that he wasn't angry, because he could borrow a violin from Hanns.
还有呢
And?
他问我们在做什么…
He asked what we were doing...
还有呢 - 没有了 吃了意大利面
And? - Nothing. Eating spaghetti.
他讲我不应该告诉你他打来电话
He said I shouldn't tell you that he phoned.
我明白了
I see!
很快我们就要去度假喽
Soon we're all going on holiday!
你相信他吗
And you believe him?
我不认为你爸让你对我撒谎是对的
I don't think it's right that your father told you to lie to me.
你应该停止争吵
You should stop arguing.
我感到抱歉
I'm sorry!
你有爱人吗
Do you have a lover?
你怎么能这样问
You think you can just ask like this?
那又怎样 - 疯子
So what? - Madness!
别隐瞒
Don't lie!
你疯了吗 - 快告诉我
Are you crazy? - Just tell me!
好吧 - 不 我不想知道
Alright. - No, I don't want to know.
玛丽 我爱你 别这样看着我…
Marie, I love you. Don't look at me like that...
完了 - 真的吗
these things happen. - Really?
但是你说过 人和人是有所不同的
But you said, this is one and the other one is different.
这叫多疑
It's called paranoia.
混淆了现实和恐惧 你需要专业的帮助
To mix up reality with fear. You need professional help.
一位心理医生或者什么东西像这样
A psychiatrist or something like that!
最好是和我上床
Better sleep with me.
喂 在吗
Yes, hello?
喂 - 我在
Hello? - Yes?
听着
Listen!
你仍然在那里吗 - 是
Are you still there? - Sure.
你记得吗
Do you remember?
当然 但是我快没时间了…
Of course, but I don't have time right now...
抱歉… - 你还好吗
Sorry... - How are you?
是的 我还好…
Yes, I feel just great...
听着 玛丽 我明天回来 - 好的 明天是…
Listen, Marie, I'll come by tomorrow. - Yes, tomorrow is...
明天很好
Tomorrow is fine.
没问题吗 - 是的
Is that okay? - Yes.
你能做到吗 - 能
Can you make it? - Yes.
要是…
What if...
我做不到
I don't make it?
半夜时候 你们在这里做什么
What are you doing here in the middle of the night?
我们是精神急症科人员 能和你谈谈吗
We are from the psychiatric emergency service. Could we talk to you?
不行 孩子们已经睡了 - 我们希望亲眼确认
No way, my children are asleep. - We'd like to see this for ourselves.
你丈夫来电话说你威胁要自杀…
Your husband phoned and said you threatened to kill yourself...
好 看向我
There, look at me.
你喝醉了吗
Are you drunk?
每个德国人晚上都会喝一杯
Every German has a drink in the evening.
两个小孩都睡着了 脉搏正常
Both children are asleep. Pulse is normal.
这根本是诽谤
That's scandalous!
非常抱歉 但这是我们的职责所在…
I'm sorry, but we were informed and it's our duty...
这简直是侮辱
This is so humiliating.
喂
Yes?
听着 如果你需要帮助或支援 请联系我们
Listen, if you need help or support, please call us.
没有什么麻烦是不能解决的…
There's nothing wrong with having a problem one can't solve...
我丈夫就有一个麻烦 还不小…
My husband has a problem, not a small one...
他听上去很绝望 他不知道要做些什么
He sounded desperate. He didn't know what else to do.
他应该自己回来 没人能强迫他
He should have come himself. - No one can force him.
我是不太好 但还能应付
I'm not great, but I cope.
我有朋友 并不需要你们
I have friends. I don't need you.
好吧 如果还有…
Well, if there is anything...
这混蛋
That asshole!
中央车站
CENTRAL STATION
托马斯
Thomas.
要是我怀孕了怎么办
What if I am pregnant?
说这个太早了 - 但是如果呢
It's too early to say. - But if?
我们会打掉它
Then we'll have an abortion.
你好
Hello!
你好 安娜
Hello, Anna!
你想要进来吗 他不在这里
Do you want to come in? He isn't here.
我知道
I know.
你接着去睡觉 好吗
Then you go to sleep, okay?
绿茶总尝起来一股青草味
Green tea always tastes just green.
你怕我伤害你吗
Are you afraid I'll hit you?
你可以尝试…
You can try...
好吧…
Well...
现在你知道我为何没再联络了
Now you know why I didn't call anymore.
我常常会想到你 一直是…
I've often thought about you. The whole time...
我跟他也说过… - 噢 谢谢
I talked to him too... - Oh, thanks!
这是错的 我们的方式…
It was wrong... the way we...
我又忙于孩子 还有巡展…
And I was so busy with the child, and being on tour...
是啊 孩子占据了你们很大一部分 - 是的 完全是
Yes, children take a lot out of you. - Yes, totally.
还有艺术品 服装… 每件事
And the artwork, the costumes... Everything.
现在他们又有了舞蹈家
And they have dancers now.
你见过他们吗
Have you met them?
打断一下…
To break off...
那个时候 不是仅仅对你 而是对任何人
not only with you, but with everybody in that time,
就像是自我惩罚
that was like self-punishment.
我从没有成为过一个整体的一部分 也从没有这么快乐过…
I never was part of a group before, and never so happy...
现在呢
And now?
你快乐吗
Are you happy?
很高兴能和你说话
I'm glad we're talking.
这里有些闷热…
It's kind of sticky in here...
真的吗
Really?
我们应该在白天见面
We should meet during the day and talk.
今天时间太短了…
Today it's all a little too much...
恩 抱歉
Sure, I'm sorry.
你可以给我打电话 - 好 我很乐意
You can call me. - Yes, I like to.
明天 我们休假 然后… - 我得离开了 我只是想来看看你
Tomorrow, we're off, but then... - I'm going, just wanted to see you.
有些遗憾 真的
A pity, but sure.
我有落下一把小提琴在这里吗 - 没
Did I leave a violin case here? - No.
你来的时候是空手 告诉我…
You had nothing when you came. Tell me...
你又开始演奏了吗 - 整天都在
Are you playing again? - All day long.
一切顺利
All the best.
恩 拜
Yes, bye.
我一回来就立刻联络你 - 好的
I'll call immediately on my return. - Okay.
拜 - 拜
Bye. - Bye.
拜 拜… - 拜托 关上门
Bye, bye... - Come on, close the door!
请到沃尔德克堡
Castle Waldeck, please.
这就走
Off we go.
你看上去不错… - 恩
You look great... - Yes.
很好 - 什么
Great. - What is it?
快点 我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
我感觉很糟糕
I feel stupid somehow.
我累得要死 我想就这么待着
I'm dead tired. I'm staying.
让保姆走吧 我们还是会付她薪水
Drop the babysitter off, we'll still pay her.
噢 别 玛丽… - 不要逼我
Oh no, Marie... - Don't push me.
明天 我们愉快地用早餐 好吗
We'll have a lovely breakfast tomorrow, alright?
我该让你在这下车吗
Should I drop you off here?
是的 谢谢你
Yes. Thank you.
或许我该返回… - 我已经关掉了计程器
Or should I go back... - I already switched off the meter.
有人吗
Hello?
我捡到一把乐师的乐器
I've got an instrument for the musicians.
我要怎么进去
How do I get in?
从门走
Through the door.
有人吗
Hello?
现在轮到你了
Now it's your turn!
沃
Whoops!
抱歉 园丁让我进来了
Sorry, the gardener let me in.
我捡到把叫提昂尼奥的乐师的小提琴
I have a violin for a musician of the "Trioneo".
唉 我想这是桩抢劫案
Phew, and I thought it was a hold-up.
我希望你不要失望 - 我希望你是捡到一套衣服
I hope you aren't disappointed. - I hope you've got a costume.
从这下去 往左就是乐师们的更衣室
Down there, to the left is the musicians' dressing room.
所有人都在吗 - 不 只有他
Is everybody there already? - No. Just him.
看看谁来了 - 还不赖…
There you are! - Not bad...
很棒啊
It's great!
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
我的小猫咪
My little pussycat.
你必须离开了 赫尔穆特随时可能过来
You have to go, Helmut will be here any minute.
就让他来吧 米兹 总有一天…
Just let him come, Mietzi. One day...
总有一天我们都会死
One day we'll all be dead.
抱歉…
Sorry...
请进
Come in, please.
别弄出噪音 孩子们在隔壁睡觉
Don't make a racket, the children are sleeping next door today.
你还有什么需要
What else do you want?
能给我一支烟吗
May I have a cigarette?
她杀害了自己的孩子 - 玛丽亚·卡拉斯
She killed her own children. - Maria Callas?
美狄亚
Medea.
报复她的丈夫 他为别的女人离开了她
Revenge on her husband. He left her for someone else.
十分正确
Quite right!
米兹…
Mietzi...
鲍尔施米特吵醒我们了 - 这里没有鲍尔施米特啊
Bauerschmidt woke us up! - There's no Bauerschmidt here.
他刚才从我们房间走过… - 胡说八道
He just walked through our room... - Nonsense!
我们想要一杯热可可和一则故事… - 没有热可可
We want a hot chocolate and a story... - No hot chocolate!
如果你们愿意 我可以给你们读一则故事
I can read you a story if you like.
这两个孩子因挨饿而无法入睡…
"The two children couldn't sleep because they were hungry...
又听见了继母对父亲说的话
and had heard what the stepmother had said to the father.
格雷特尔哭着对汉塞尔说
Gretel cried and said to Hansel:
“现在我们完了”
"Now we're doomed."
但汉塞尔说道 “别担心 格雷特尔 我会找到一条出路的”
But Hansel said: "Don't worry, Gretel, I'll find a way out."
然后等到大人们睡着了…
"And when the grown-ups slept..."
怎么了 - 我受够了
What? - Enough!
别这样纠缠
Don't shuffle like that.
他在这里 我看见了 这一次…
He was here. I saw him. This time...
别吼
Don't shout!
看 那是鲍尔施米特 - 是啊
See? It WAS Bauerschmidt! - Yes!
我要读下去吗 - 我一点也不在乎
Shall I read on? - I don't give a damn!
那只猩猩到底想干什么 - 你到底在说什么
What does the ape want here? - Who are you talking about?
别瞒着我 别这样 看着我
Don't lie to me. Not like that, not to my face!
到底怎么回事
What's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
天啊 又是你 - 抱歉…
Jesus, you again! - Sorry...
孩子们睡不着 - 妈妈 鲍尔施米特来过…
The children couldn't sleep. - Mum, Bauerschmidt was here...
然后赫尔穆特回来了 然后… - 是 是 是 是
and then Helmut came, and... - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah...
我要杀了他 然后你 然后我自己
I'll kill him! And then you, and then myself!
你疯了吗 就这样吧 安静些 - 别跟我说这些
Are you crazy? That's it, be quiet! - Don't tell me this.
你能听见他有多疯狂 - 赫尔穆特 请你现在就离开
You can hear how crazy he is. - And Helmut, please leave now.
我不想再见到你
I don't want to see you again.
这里除了我之外没人 - 她在撒谎
There was no one here but me. - She's lying.
这不关我事 好吗
This is none of my business, okay?
我什么都不想知道 明白吗 - 是的 那好
I want no part of that, is that clear? - Yes, alright.
那么 就这样吧 我数到20然后你们就入睡
So, that's it. I count to 20 and then both of you sleep.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Eighteen.
Nineteen.
谢谢你 这真是太好了
Thank you, that's very kind.
我自己有两个孩子
I've got two myself.
年纪要小些
A little younger.
你很想和他们躺一块儿吗…
You really want to lie down with them...
不 今天不了 你有我可以穿的衣服吗
No, not today. Do you by any chance have a costume for me?
我有一整箱
I've got a whole trunk full of them.
最重要的是 你不该看起来这么吸引人
Most important, you shouldn't look attractive!
谢谢你 - 玩开心
Thank you. - Have fun.
你能载我一程吗 - 发生什么了
Can you pick me up? - What happened?
我身上有很多精液…
There was so much semen, it was all over me...
洗不掉了 - 听着糟透了 你去哪里了
And nothing to clean it off. - Sounds awful. Where did you go?
楼下 庭院里的长椅上
Downstairs, on a bench. In the garden.
你个猪
You pig!
你知道他后来做了什么吗 - 不知道
Do you know what he did then? - No.
他脱下他的袜子替我擦脸
He took off his sock and cleaned my face.
我要吐了…
I'm going to barf...
奇怪了…
Strange...
我喜欢这样
I liked it.
留意只穿一只袜子的人 对吗
Look out for someone who wears just one sock, okay?
汉斯
Hanns!
玛丽
Marie?
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
托马斯把他的小提琴落在家里了 - 我知道
Thomas left his violin at home. - I know.
他知道你在这里吗 - 他不需要知道
Does he know that you're here? - He doesn't need to.
好吧 无所谓 你看上去不错
Yeah, whatever. You look great.
谢谢 能给我一支烟吗
Thanks. Got a cigarette?
你想等着托马斯吗
Do you want to wait for Thomas?
要我去拿些喝的吗
Shall I get us something to drink?
我想我犯相思病了
I think I'm lovesick.
真有趣 我还以为你不知道那是什么意思
Funny, I thought you wouldn't know what it meant.
我一直以为你是蕾丝边 - 什么
I always thought you were a lesbian. - What?
是啊
Yes.
蕾丝边就从不犯相思病吗
And lesbians are never lovesick?
我不知道 管它的呢 你是吗
Don't know, don't give a shit. Are you?
不是
No.
我不知道 不太清楚 为什么你这么说
Not that I know, I don't know. Why do you say such a thing?
好吧 你看上去似乎不在乎
Well, it looked like you didn't seem to care.
不在乎什么 - 好吧…
About what? - Well...
托马斯和那个女人…
Thomas and the women...
我第一次听说
First time I've heard of it.
可是 太明显了 每个人都知道
Well, it was so obvious, everybody knew.
我就不知道 为什么你从没跟我说过
I didn't. Why didn't you ever tell me anything?
我告诉你了 我以为你是蕾丝边
Told you, thought you were a lesbian.
以为你们俩有某种交易 没人知道真实的情况 我是说…
Thought the two of you had some kind of a deal. Nobody knows, I mean...
从没见过你和别的男人一起 但你也一定有性生活吧
Never saw you with another man. But you must have had sex?
不 - 不什么
No! - No?
什么样的结论啊
What a conclusion.
一个男人对自己的妻子不忠 所以她就必须变得性冷淡…
A man cheats on his wife, so she has to be frigid...
或者是蕾丝边
or a lesbian.
你清楚 我知道些什么吗
You know, what do I know?
你总是什么都知道 汉斯 - 是啊 我明白
You always know everything, Hanns. - Yes, I know.
小提琴在桌上
The violin is on the table.
1 2 3 4…
One, two, three, four...
哎唷
Ouch!
不知道明天要怎么去做
Don't know how to do the thing tomorrow.
什么
What?
我不知道怎么办… - 你在说些什么
I don't know how... - What do you mean?
我害怕谈论我的问题 - 你是什么意思
I'm afraid to talk about my problems. - What do you mean?
我必须跟你父亲讲 参加试演… 我做不到
I have to talk to your father, what to play at the audition... I can't do it.
你当然可以 - 我极度紧张
Sure you can! - I'm ULTRA stressed.
我知道你也一样 但为什么 - 你要演奏什么
I know, you are too, but why? - What will you play?
柴可夫斯基
Tchaikovsky.
真消沉 - 我撤掉了
How low. - I cancel.
废话 他讨厌柴可夫斯基 - 或许这还不算太坏
Nonsense, he hates Tchaikovsky! - Perhaps that's not so bad.
演奏巴赫 - 什么
Play Bach. - What?
奏鸣曲独奏 简单 我有极好的记录
Solo Sonata! Simple! I've a great record.
不 不行 我宁可睡觉也不讨论这个
No, don't get it. I'd rather sleep than talk.
我很快把它拿来
I'll fetch it quickly.
别 我已经… 我去沙发上睡了
No, I'm already de... I sleep on the couch.
拜托 会有成效的
Come here, it'll work out.
让他谈论巴赫 他热衷于此
Let him talk about Bach, he loves Bach.
好吧 也许这样更好
Yes, maybe that's better.
当然了 抱歉…
Absolutely! Sorry...
我主耶稣
Jesus Christ.
如果我在做梦 此刻请将我唤醒…
If I'm dreaming, please wake me up now...
当你问时 你已经认识到了真相
You recognise reality when you ask:
这是梦吗
Is this a dream?
在梦中你从不会问 我是否在做梦
Whilst dreaming you never say: "Do I dream?"
在梦中一切只是发生着…
In a dream everything just happens...
就像行人路过乞丐
like pedestrians passing a beggar.
天啊…
Oh God...
你可以叫我瓦伦汀…
You can call me Valentin...
爸爸
Dad!
过来 陪我坐着 和我喝一杯
Come, sit with me. Have a drink with me.
我不好意思独自喝酒
I'm embarrassed to drink alone.
就快开始了…
It's about to start...
焰火
The fireworks.
你看见了吗
Did you see that?
我看见什么了
What did I see?
我看到一个金发女人 个子高高的 修长的腿…
I see a blonde woman, tall, straight legs...
多情可人
and enough dramatic expression to break everyone's heart.
爸爸 那是我 玛丽 - 玛丽
Dad, it's me, Marie. - Marie?
你的女儿
Your daughter?!
小猫…
Kitten...
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
你瞧 我的眼镜让我头疼
You see, my glasses give me a headache.
你试图和我调情
You tried to hit on me!
没有的事 我想要观看焰火
No. I wanted to watch the fireworks.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没什么
Nothing.
吉赛尔在哪儿 你独自一人吗 - 糟糕的派对 对吗
Where is Giselle? Are you alone? - Terrible party, hmm?
你为什么没有打给我 你人来汉堡的时候
Why don't you call me, when you're in Hamburg?
我明天得去萨尔茨堡
I have to go to Salzburg tomorrow.
你最后一次见孩子们是在… 等等 在你的生日上
Last time you saw the children, was... wait, at your birthday.
他们已经上大学了吗
Are they already at college?
莱昂尼快上学前班 艾略特快上幼稚园
Leonie will go to preschool soon, Elliot will go to nursery.
然后你就能够再次工作了
Then you'll be able to work again.
你知道你随时都可以回来
You know that you can come back anytime.
托马斯在试用期 我们随时可以撵走他
Thomas is on probation. We can get rid of him.
不管怎样他爱好流行更多
Anyhow he loves this pop thing a lot.
爸爸 你在暗示什么 - 你一直要比他优秀
Dad, what are you suggesting? - You've always been better than him.
没人配得上你
Nobody is good enough for you.
你仍然有练习吗 - 爸爸
You're still practising, aren't you? - Dad!
托马斯有别的女人 另一幢房子 孩子…
Thomas has another woman. Another house, children...
每样东西他都有两件 复制品 你懂吗
He has two of everything. A duplicate, do you understand?
我的天啊
Jesus!
那你可以靠着那些流行东西得到一大笔钱
So you can make a lot of money with that pop stuff.
如今你可以袖手旁观 看那个蠢货度过他的余生…
Now can you watch that idiot spending the rest of his life...
不停地工作来扶养你
working to keep you.
好注意 美好生活
Great idea! Great life!
我一直告诉你他一无是处
I always told you that he's a good for nothing!
爸爸 我的心受伤了
Dad, my heart is wounded!
请安慰我
Please comfort me.
过来
Come!
我不不知道我为何还在这里…
I don't know why I'm still here...
恩 那么回家去吧 小猫…
Well, then go home, kitten...
我想和他谈谈 -几时
I want to talk with him! - When?
在这里 现在吗
Here? Now?
怎么了 - 没什么 一切总会好转
What's wrong? - No, everything is alright.
我将重蹈妈妈的覆辙
I'm going to have the same life as Mum.
抱歉 但你对我来说太沉了
Sorry, but you're too heavy for me!
我将像她一样 抑郁地坐在屋里 吓唬着孩子
I'll be like her, sitting depressed at home, terrorising the children.
你妈妈是个病妇 你… 有天赋 你有乐器
Your mother is a sick woman. You... have talent. You have an instrument.
妈妈也一样
So did Mum.
她抚养了两个孩子 她曾经可以拥有事业如果你让
She raised two kids. If you had done that, she could have had a career.
抱歉 亲爱的 你不清楚这事
Sorry, darling. You're confusing the matter.
我遇见你妈时 我完全知道我想要什么 但她不是
When I met your mother, I knew exactly what I wanted. She did not!
她没有胆量 你本可以支持她
She didn't dare. You could have supported her!
我必须顾及我自己 那时候才刚起步
I had to look after myself. It was only the beginning.
而接着她有了一个孩子
And then she had a child.
是你们俩有了一个孩子 那是我
Both of you had a child! That was ME!
拜托 坐下来吧
Come on, sit down.
我们再多待会儿 看 是焰火
We still have so much time together. Look, the fireworks.
玛丽
Marie?
托马斯 我要开始了…
Thomas, I begin...
赫尔穆特 你现在必须回家去了 - 是啊 是啊
Helmut, you have to go home now! - Yes, yes.
他们真棒 是吧
They are great, hm?
站起来 别跌倒了…
Stand up! Don't fall...
我该怎么从这里出去 - 这里没有出口
How do I get out of here? - There is no way out.
你叫什么名字 - 乔纳森
What's your name? - Jonathan.
乔纳森 抱紧我
Jonathan, hold me tight.
乔纳森
Jonathan!
你怎么回事 你想折磨我吗
What's wrong? Do you want to wear me down?
看看你的所作所为
And the way you look!
你的袜子在哪儿
And where is your sock?
什么 你喝醉了吗 - 你这混蛋
What? Are you drunk? - You bastard!
你对我的人生做了什么
What did you do to my life?!
不 我离开 - 玛丽
No, I'm leaving! - Marie!
希望你们俩会对你们的所作所为感到快乐 而且尿在彼此身上
Hope you'll both be happy with what you did, and piss on each other!
为什么你不在家 孩子们在哪儿
Why aren't you home? Where are the children?
好像你真的在意似的 - 你妈妈和他们在一起吧…
As if that would interest you THAT much! - Your mother is with them...
你他妈的闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
很好 我们能回到这个问题上吗 你妈妈有没有和他们在一起
Fine, we can go on talking like this. Is your mother with them?
只有他们俩
They are alone.
他们睡着了而且再不会醒来
They sleep and will never wake up again.
而且在解决了你之后 我再自刎
And after I'm through with you, I'll slash myself!
你完全疯了 我一个字都不敢相信
You are totally crazy! I don't believe a single word!
你好 再见 没事了现在…
Yes, bye, it's over...
我的孩子们…
My little ones...
我希望他们仍安睡着…
I hope they're still asleep...
当然 他们都睡着了
Sure. They're asleep.
告诉我这些都结束了…
Tell me that it'll be over...
说你爱我 跟我说一切都会好起来…
Say that you love me, tell me that everything will be fine...
哭 总是哭…
The crying... Always the crying...
如果你总哭那要怎么才说得清
One can't talk, if you always cry.
你们都一样
You're all the same.
你个鸡巴
Penis!
是啊…
Yeah...
是啊 这就是你所想的
Yeah, that's what you think.
但是你错了 亲爱的 你都错了
But you are wrong, my dear. All of you are wrong.
你不明白 但你对此无能为力
You don't understand. But you can't help it!
它就在你体内 你被迫怀生育…
It's inside of you! You're compelled to procreate...
它胜过了你的理智 别人必须就要迁就着你
it's stronger than your intellect. One has to be careful with you.
有任何人问过我吗
Did anybody ask me?
有 我问过 - 然后我怎么说
Yes, I did! - And what did I say?
操 妈的
Fuck, shit!
我不想那些
I didn't want that!
但那不重要了 那不是我的全部
But that doesn't matter. It wasn't about me at all.
你只想着你那愚蠢的浪漫 为人母的感觉
You just wanted your stupid romantic, motherly feelings!
来 站起来 你必须控制住你自己
Come, get up. You have to get hold of yourself.
我带孩子们度假 你也会有所好转的
I take the children with me on holiday, and you get better.
别从我身旁带走孩子 - 停止胡闹
Don't take the children away from me. - Stop this nonsense!
去度假吧 到海边旅行 休息一下
Go on holiday too, travel to the sea. Get some rest.
带上女伴 萨布里娜怎么样
Take a girlfriend. What about Sabrina?
我什么都没了 我什么都不想…
I've got nothing. I... I don't want anything.
都结束了 是吗
It's over, isn't it?
是他干的
He did it.
林中房屋失火了
The forester's house is burning!
玛丽
Marie?
快过来 不会有事的
Come on, this won't lead to anything today.
感谢上帝 我们提早拿到了报酬
Thank heavens that we got paid in advance!
她走了 - 是吗 你送走她的吗
She's gone! - Well, you did send her away.
她那么愤怒…
She was so angry...
是啊 每天都是 当你有了自己的演奏会的时候 女人都这样
Yes, today of all days. When you had your concert. Typical woman!
楼下有很多鬼魂
Under the stairs is a lot of spirit.
如果你想 我可以帮你把它们都烧毁
If you want, I can help you burn it all down.
拜 乔纳森
Bye, Jonathan.
嘿
Hey!
这幢漂亮的老房子…
This beautiful old house...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你见到乔纳森了吗
Did you see Jonathan?
没有
No.
你有烟吗
Do you have a cigarette?
你有孩子吗
Do you have children?
我发觉有些欣慰的是你不想和我睡觉
I find it comforting that you don't want to sleep with me.
那还能做些什么
What else then?
是啊 没了
Oh, no!
晚上好
Evening.
你见到乔纳森了吗 - 没
Did you see Jonathan? - No.
看起来像恶意纵火
Looks like malicious arson.
赫尔穆特在哪儿
Where is Helmut?
赫尔穆特
Helmut!
在吗 - 你迷路了吗
Hello! - Did you get lost?
出来吧 赫尔穆特 - 乔纳森
Come on, Helmut! - Jonathan!
赫尔穆特
Helmut!
嘿 我可以拿回夹克吗
Say, could I have the jacket back?
这是特供的一件 - 当然
It's an individual piece. - Sure!
拜
Bye.
噢 人来了…
Oh, man...